Sarah Newton

Full-stack web developer. User interface developer.



s.newton2990@gmail.com



+46 725 663 913



/sarah-newton-66077553

SUMMARY

Full-stack developer with g+ years professional experience, specialising in user experience, front-end development and user research. As a full-stack developer with a proven history in user experience and interface design, I strive to maintain a UX-centric mindset when developing in order to deliver products of the highest standard, providing a great experience for the end customers. Currently developing using React.js, Typescript with C# Asp.Net frameworks. Originally from Brisbane, Australia with international experience and professional work history across Sweden, Japan and Australia.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Bokio Group, Gothenburg, Sweden Full-stack Developer

MAY 2017 - CURRENT

- Maintaining Bokio's web application using React.js and C# ASP.Net.
- Developing new features including third-party integrations.
- Specialising in improving user experience and user interaction in order to increase user happiness.
- Evaluating new projects based on customer feedback and data research

Phase New Media. Brisbane. Australia Front-End Developer/ Designer (6 week contract)

NOVEMBER 2016 - DECEMBER 2016

- Maintaining front-end code base and implementing new functionality for clients.
- Creation of email marketing design concepts.
- UI modifications to existing and new website concepts.

Muse Melbourne, Melbourne, Australia *UI Designer (Freelance)*

APRIL 2016 - JULY 2016

- Responsible for user interface design across desktop, tablet and
- Quick turnaround of designs and mockups in order to meet tight deadlines.
- Goal to prepare a small start-up for potential investment opportunities

SKILLS

Web development

- React.js
- Javascript
- Typescript
- HTML
- CSS / Sass / Less
- C#
- ASP Net
- Java

User experience research

User interface design

Data analysis

SOFTWARE & TOOLS

Azure DevOps

Git

Visual Studio

Webpack

MailChimp

EDUCATION & TRAINING

La Trobe University

Melbourne. Australia Bachelor of Politics and Sustainable Development

MARCH 2016 - 2020

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE (CONT)

Venue10, London, England (Based in Tokyo, Japan) Lead User Experience/User Interface Developer (3 month contract)

SEPTEMBER 2014 - DECEMBER 2014

- Development of wireframes, interface mockups and user workflows for a small start-up.
- Final designs developed in HTML, CSS and JavaScript ready for backend integration.
- Organising and managing a small digital team from abroad.
- Ability to manage time scheduling effectively.

Flight Centre, Brisbane, Australia Web and User Interface Designer

JANUARY 2013 - JULY 2014

- Working in the UX/UI team and optimising user interaction.
- Implement design prototypes in HTML and CSS.
- Develop wireframes through to complete interface designs.
- Social media promotional and online competition creative.
- Creation of digital marketing campaigns to increase conversion.
- Responsible for directing and training new/junior digital designers.

Phase New Media, Brisbane, Australia *Digital Media Producer*

JANUARY 2011 - JANUARY 2013

- Website designs and mockups from client brief.
- Front-end development of web and mobile using HTML and CSS.
- Design, development and delivery of email marketing campaigns.
- Customer service and liaison over phone, email and in person.

EDUCATION & TRAINING (CONT)

Metropolitan South Institute of TAFE (MSIT)

Brisbane, Australia Diploma of Graphic Design 2009 - 2010

Metropolitan South Institute of TAFE (MSIT)

Brisbane, Australia Certificate IV Screen & Media 2008

INTERESTS

Rock climbing

Hiking

Vegetable gardening

Blues dancing

Good coffee

Foreign languages